Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello RG.007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series II: Subject Files, 2475
  - Subseries B: MetroTech Center, 2092
    - MetroTech Board, 1991 August - 1997 October; 2300 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - History - 1, 1988- 1994 May; 2301 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - History - 2, 1983 January -1997; 2302 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - History – 3, 1982 May - 1992 March; 2303 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Polytechnic University: An Overview – Presentation, 1992 May; 2304 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Carlo Lotti and Associates – Presentation – Rome, Italy, 1996 June-December; 2305 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - YMCA - Joint Venture, 1994 January; 2306 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Miquel Barcelo Visit, 2007 September; 2307 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - MetroTech Institute, 2006 August-September; 4653 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - "MetroTech Institute: An Interdisciplinary Institute to Address Critical Urban Problems", 2006 September 5; 4654 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated; 4655 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Wainova: World Alliance for Innovation, 2008-2009; 4656 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - MetroTech BID Website Info, 2007 September; 4657 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - MetroTech Real Estate, 1997 March 22; 4658 (Box 27, Folder 36)
- Series III: Publications and Manuscripts, 4342
  This series contains published and unpublished scholarly articles and manuscripts written and edited by George Bugliarello as well as his handwritten notes and research material he used for various publications. The publications and reports have been assigned a number based on a numbering system adopted by the Chancellor's office to keep track of publications. A list of these publications has been inserted in the front of Box 28 for reference.
  This series is arranged by document type. The publications and reports and newspaper articles are arranged according to the publication number assigned by the donor and are otherwise ordered chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Publications and Reports (#3-#326, M, N), 3124
    - #3 - Bugliarello, G., "La Resistenza al Moto Accelerato di Sfere in Acqua" (The Resistance to Accelerated Motion of Spheres in Water), La Ricerca Scientifica, Vol. 26, No. 2, (Feb. 1956), pp. 437-461., 3125 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - #4 - Ippen, A.T., J.W. Daily and G. Bugliarello, "Pertinent Factors in Flow Research on Dilute Fiber Suspensions," Tappi, Vol. 40, No. 6, (June 1957), pp. 478-486., 3126 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - #6 - Daily, J.W. and G. Bugliarello, "The Effects of Fibers on Velocity Distribution, Turbulence and Flow Resistance of Dilute Suspensions," MIT Hydrodynamics Laboratory, Technical Report #30, (Oct. 1958)., 3127 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - #21 - Bugliarello, G., "Some Considerations on the Analysis and Design of Hydraulic Machinery for Non-Newtonian Fluids," Proceedings, 1963 Meeting of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, London, pp. 1-8., 3128 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - #22 - Bugliarello, G. and V.Bahvnagri, "The Role of Flood Plains in the Correlation Between Flood Prediction and Dam Design," Proceedings, 1963 Meeting of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, London, pp. 21-28, 3129 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - #23 - Bugliarello, G. and G.C.C. Hsiao, "Phase Separation in Suspensions Flowing Through Bifurcations: A Simplified Hemodynamic Model," Science, Vol.143, No. 3605, (Jan. 31, 1964), pp. 469-471., 3130 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - #24 - Bugliarello, G., "Flow of Clay-Water Suspensions," (Discussion) Journal of Hydraulics Division, ASCE, Vol.90, (HYI), (1964), pp. 67-69., 3131 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - #25 - Bugliarello, G., "Man-Machine Communication in Civil Engineering," (Discussion) Journal Structural Division, ASCE, 90, (STI), (1964), pp. 253-255., 3132 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - #26 - Bugliarello, G. and C. C. Hsiao, "The Mechanism of Phase Separation at Bifurcations," Proceedings of the Third European Conference on Microcirculation, (R.G. Harders, Ed.), (1965), pp. 363-367., 3133 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - #27 - Bugliarello, G. and E. D. Jackson, III, "Random Walk Study of Convective Diffusion," Proceedings of the ASCE, Engineering Mechanics Division. Vol. 90, No. EM4, (Aug. 1964), pp. 49-77., 1964 August; 3134 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - #28 - Bugliarello, G., C. Kapur and G.C.C. Hsiao, "The Profile Viscosity and Other Characteristics of Blood Flow in Non-uniform Shear Field," Transaction, 4th International Congress on Rheology, Vol. 4, (1965), pp. 351-370., 3135 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - #30 - Bugliarello, G., "Exploratory Studies on the Stochastic Simulation of Outfall Flows," Proceedings, 1965 Meeting of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, Leningrad, 1965., 3136 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - #31 - Bugliarello, G., "Hospitals," Carnegie Review, No. 5, (Summer, 1965), 3137 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - #32 - Bugliarello, G., "Microcirculation Hemodynamics and Other Biological Flow Problems: A Progress Report," Biological Flows Symposium, ASME, pp. 192-208, April 1965., 1965 April; 3138 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - #33 - Bhavnagri, V. and G. Bugliarello, "Mathematical Representation of an Urban Flood Plain," Journal of the Hydraulics Division, Proceedings ASCE, No. HY2, (March 1965), pp. 149-173., 1965 March; 3139 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - #34 - Bugliarello, G., C. Behn, C.E. Carver, E.M. Krokosky, J.R. Ripken and R. Shiffman, "Non-Newtonian Flows--Their Value in Civil Engineering," Civil Engineering, August 1965., 1965 August; 3140 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - #35 - Brandt, A. and G. Bugliarello, "A Simplified Model of the Flow in the Plasmatic Gaps of the Smaller Circulatory Vessels," Proceedings, 18th Annual Conference on Engineering in Medicine and Biology, Philadelphia, Pa., (Nov. 1965), p. 159., 1965 November; 3141 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - #36 - Bugliarello, G., "An Engineering-Oriented View of Biological Flows in the Relation of Engineering Mechanics Research to the Practice of Civil Engineering," EMD Specialty Conference, Proceedings, ASCE, (Oct. 1966), pp. 263-281., 1966 October; 3142 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - #38 - Bhavnagri, V.S. and G. Bugliarello, "Flood Proofing in a Flood Plain: A Stochastic Model," Journal of the Hydraulics Division, Proceedings of the ASCE, Vol. 92, No. HY4, (July 1966) pp. 63-76., 1966 July; 3143 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - #39 - Brandt, A. and G. Bugliarello, "Concentration Redistribution Phenomena in the Shear Flow of Monolayers of Suspended Particles," Transactions of the Society of Rheology, Vol. 10, No. 1, (1966), pp. 2-29-251., 3144 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - #40 - Bugliarello, G., J.T. Gormley, W.A. McNally and J. Onstott, "HYDRO, A Computer Language for Water Resources Engineering," Civil Engineering, ASCE, (Nov. 1966), 1966 November; 3145 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - #43 - Bugliarello, G., "Programming Needs in the Water Resources Field and the Role of a Problem-Oriented Language," Proceedings, IBM Scientific Computation Symposium on Environmental Data, (Nov. 1966), pp. 165-184., 1966 November; 3146 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - #44 - Bugliarello, G. and E.D. Jackson, III, "Study of Convective Diffusion from Continuous Point Sources by a Random Walk Model," Proceedings, 5th U.S. National Congress of Applied Mechanics, ASME, New York, (1966), (Abstract), p. 738., 3147 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - #46 - Quevedo, C. and G. Bugliarello, "Stochastic Simulation of the Diffusion of Jets," Proceedings, XII Congress of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, Fort Collins, Colorado, (1967), pps.146-155., 3148 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - #48 - Bugliarello, G., "The Role and Development of Problem-Oriented Computer Languages in Water Resources Technology," Proceedings, International Conference on Water for Peace, Washington, D.C., Vol. 6, pp. 573-585., Undated; 3149 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - #49 - Bugliarello, G., "Developing Creativity in an Engineering Science Course--Socrates Revisited," Journal of Engineering Education, Vol. 59, (March 1969) pp. 877-880., 1969 March; 3150 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - #50 - Bugliarello, G. and J.F. Sevilla, "Aspectos de la Hidrodinamica de Suspensiones on Sistemas Microscopicos," Proceedings, II Congreso Latioamericano de Hidraulica, 1968., 3151 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - #51 - Bugliarello, G. and J.W. Hoskins, "Stochastic Simulation of Convective Diffusion in the Axial Plasmatic Gaps of Capillaries," Proceedings, 19th Annual Conference of Engineering in Medicine and Biology, San Francisco, (Nov. 1966), p. 183., 1966 November; 3152 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - #52 - Bugliarello, G and G.C.C. Hsiao, "Numerical Simulation of Three- Dimensional Flow in the Axial Plasmatic Gaps of Capillaries," Proceedings, 7th International Conference on Medical and Biological Engineering, Stockholm, (Aug. 18, 1967), p. 376., 1967 August; 3153 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - #53 - Bugliarello, G. and J. T. Onstott, "A Progress Report on HYDRO," Proceedings of IBM Scientific Computing Symposium on Water and Air Resources Management, Yorktown Heights, New York, (October 23-25 1967), pps. 197-191., 1967 October; 3154 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - #54 - Bugliarello, G., Bioengineering Philosophy and Overview (Discussion), "Dimensions of Biomedical Engineering," (E. Salkovitz, L. Gere¬nde, L. Wingard, Eds.) San Francisco Press, (1968), pp. 55-72., 3155 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - #55 - Bugliarello, G. and C.E. Quevedo, "Stochastic Models for Diffusion," (Discussion), Proceedings, 12th Congress of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, Fort Collins, Colorado, Vol. 5, (1967), pp. 581-587., 3156 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - #56 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and the Biomachine Interface," Chapter in Bioengineering--An Engineering View, (G. Bugliarello, Ed.), San Francisco Press, (1968), pp. 1-16., 3157 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - #57 - Bhavnagri, V. and G. Bugliarello, "Flood Proofing in A Flood Plain: A Stochastic Model," (Discussion), ASCE, Journal of Hydraulics Division, pp. 542-545, March 1968., 1968 March; 3158 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - #58 - Bugliarello, G. and J. Sevilla, "The Peripheral Plasma Layer in Pulsatile Flow in Hollow Glass Fibers," in Advances in the Microcirculation, H. Harders (Ed.) Vol. 2, p. 80-87, S. Karger, Basel, 1969., 3159 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - #59 - Bugliarello, G. and G. Yanizeski, "Some Phase-Separation Phenomena in Iso-Density Two-Phase Flows," in Advances on Solid-Liquid Flow in Pipes and Its Applications, I. Zandi (Ed.), Pergamon Press, NY, pp. 73- 85, 1971., 3160 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - #60 - Bugliarello, G., "Rheology of Blood" in Biomaterials, (L. Stark and G. Agarwal, Eds.) Plenum Press, pp. 93-102, 1969., 3161 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - #61 - Bugliarello, G., "The Definition of the Role of the Nations' Universities in the Solution of Urban Problems," Proceedings, Conference on Urban Problems, Denver, Colorado, Sept. 1968, (Texas A&M for Dept. of Housing and Urban Development)., 1968 September; 3162 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - #62 - Bugliarello, G., "Advanced Courses and Laboratories for Bioengineering," Proceedings, 5th Symposium on Bioengineering Education, Rose Polytechnic Institute, October 1968; Topic No. 5, pp. 1-3., 1968 October; 3163 (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - #63 - Bugliarello, G. and E.D. Jackson, "A Stochastic Model of Convective Diffusion from a Continuous Source," Journal of Hydraulic Research, Vol. 7, No. 2, pp. 177-204, 1969., 3164 (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - #64 - Bugliarello, G., "The Human Element in the Planning of Large Socio- Technological Systems," Proceedings, 21st Annual Conference on Engineering in Medicine and Biology, Houston, Texas, November, 1968., 1968 November; 3165 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - #65 - Bugliarello, G. and C. Wakstein, "An Overview of the Noise Pollution Problem," Proceedings, 21st Annual Conference on Engineering in Medicine and Biology, Houston, Texas, November, 1968, pp. 54-10., 1968 November; 3166 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - #66 - Bugliarello, G., T.K. Hung and E.C. James, "Model Studies of the Hydrodynamic Characteristics of an Erythrocyte. II. Drag of an Individual Erythrocyte; Erythrocyte-Wall Interaction," Proceedings, 5th International Rheology Conference, Tokyo, 1968., 3167 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - #69 - Bugliarello, G., "Teaching of Fluid Mechanics in Italy," International Symposium on the Teaching of Fluid Mechanics, La Houille Blanche, pp. 429-431, 1968., 3168 (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - #70 - Bugliarello, G., "An Introduction to the Stochastic Simulation of Flow Processes," Proceedings, NATO Advanced Institute on Surface Hydrodynamics, Bressanone, September 1969, pp. 379-423, 1969., 1969 September; 3169 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - #71 - Bugliarello, G., T.W. Calvert, T.G. Fox, T.K. Hung and M.H. Weissman, "A Study of Health Care in Western Pennsylvania," IEEE Transactions, Vol. 57, No. 11, pp. 1853-1869, November, 1969., 1969 November; 3170 (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - #72 - Bugliarello, G., J.T. Onstott and L.A. Jostes, "The Expansion of the Scope and Role of Hydro--A Problem-Oriented Language for Water Resources," Proceedings, XIIth Congress of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, Vol. A, pp. 1-8, Science Council of Japan, Kyoto, 1969., 3171 (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - #73 - Day, H.J., G. Bugliarello, P.H.P. Ho and V.T. Houghton, "Evaluation of Benefits of a Flood Warning System," Water Resources Research, Vol. 5, No. 5, pp. 937-946, October 1969., 1969 October; 3172 (Box 28, Folder 48)
    - #74 - Bugliarello, G., "The Potential of Information Theory: What Message Could be Carried by the Fluid in the Lower Urinary System?" Symposium on the Hydrodynamics of Micturition, University of Iowa, Nov. 1968, Hydrodynamics of Micturition, Charles C Thomas Publisher, pp. 378-391, 1971., 1968 November; 3173 (Box 28, Folder 49)
    - #75 - Bugliarello, G. and T.K. Hung, "Information Theory and the Ureter: A Hydrodynamic Point of View," Chapter in Urodynamics, S. Boyarsky, et al. Editors, Academic Press, 1971., 3174 (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - #76 - Bugliarello, G. and G.C. Hsiao, "A Mathematical Model of the Flow in the Axial Plasmatic Gaps of the Smaller Vessels" Biorheology, Vol. 7, pp. 5-36, 1970., 3175 (Box 28, Folder 51)
    - #77 - Bugliarello, G. and J. Sevilla, "Velocity Distribution and Other Characteristics of Steady and Pulsatile Blood Flow in Fine Glass Tubes," Biorheology, Vol. 7, pp. 1-23, Pergamon Press, 1970., 3176 (Box 28, Folder 52)
    - #78 - Bugliarello, G., General Report: "Simulation Techniques in Water Resources Systems," Proceedings XIIIth Congress of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, Kyoto, Japan, Vol. 5-2, pp. 67-83, Aug.-Sept. 1969., 1969 August-September; 3177 (Box 28, Folder 53)
    - #79 - Bugliarello, G. and C.E. Quevedo, "Stochastic Simulation of Boundary Layer Flows," Proceedings, ASCE-EMD Specialty Conference on Probabilistic Concepts and Methods in Engineering, Purdue University, pp. 47-52, November 1969., 1969 November; 3178 (Box 28, Folder 54)
    - #80 - Bugliarello, G., "Hemodynamic and Mass Transfer Implications of Phase Separation Phenomena in the Microcirculation," in Fluid Dynamics of Blood Circulation and Respiratory Flow, Proceedings, NATO Specialists Meetings, Advisory Group on Aeronautical Research and Development-(AGARD), pp. 2.1-2.8, 1970., 3179 (Box 28, Folder 55)
    - #81 - Bugliarello, G., "Critique of the Subcommittee Report on Technology Guidelines," Proceedings Invitational Conference on Automated Multi- Phasic Health Testing Facilities (AMHT), National Center for Health Services Research and Development, Washington, D.C., January 1970, pp. 199-205, Vol. 3., 1970 January; 3180 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - #82 - Bugliarello, G., M. Duffey and T.K. Hung, "Model Studies of the Hydrodynamic Characteristics of an Erythrocyte, III Drag and Lift in Erythrocyte-Erythrocyte Interaction," Proceedings, 2nd International Conference on Hemorheology, Heidelberg, July 1969. (Theoretical an Clinical Hemorheology), pp. 30-46., 1969 July; 3181 (Box 28, Folder 57)
    - #83 - Hung, T.K., M.H. Weissman and G. Bugliarello, "A Numerical Model for Two-Dimensional Oscillatory Flow and Oxygen Transfer in the Axial Plasmatic Gaps of Capillaries," Proceedings, 2nd International Conference on Hemorheology, Heidelberg, July, 1969, (Theoretical and Clinical Hemorheology) pp. 60-70., 1969 July; 3182 (Box 28, Folder 58)
    - #84 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology Forecasting for Environmental Health Physical Factors and a Proposal for a Forecasting Mechanism," Prepared for the NIEHS Task Force on Research Planning in Environmental Health Science, on deposit at the National Library of Medicine, Bethesda, Maryland (1969)., 3183 (Box 28, Folder 59)
    - #85 - Bugliarello, G., "Large Socio-Technological Systems: Human Conflict and Human Design," Global Systems Dynamics, E. Attinger, Ed., S. Karger, Publisher (N.Y.) 1970, pp. 149-55., 3184 (Box 28, Folder 60)
    - #86 - Bugliarello, G., "The Role and Development of the Programming in Language 'HYDRO' in Hydrology," Lectures, International Course for Hydrology Professors (V.T. Chow, Co-ordinator), University of Illinois at Urbana, July 1969., 1969 July; 3185 (Box 28, Folder 61)
    - #87 - Bugliarello, G., "Model Studies and Phase Separation," Hemorheology, A.L. Copley, Ed., Pergamon Press, 1970, pp. 813-14., 3186 (Box 28, Folder 62)
    - #88 - Bugliarello, G., "Some Aspects of the Biomechanics of the Microcirculation, Anno 1969," Developments in Mechanics, Vol. 5, pp. 921-62 (H.J. Weiss, D.F. Young, W.F. Riley and T.R. Rogge, Editors, Iowa State University Press, 1969)., 3187 (Box 28, Folder 63)
    - #89 - Bugliarello, G., et al, "Computer Languages and Program Libraries," Journal of the Hydraulics Division, Vol. 98, No. HY7, July 1972, pp. 1243-53., 1972 July; 3188 (Box 28, Folder 64)
    - #90 - Wong, A.K.C. and G. Bugliarello, "Artificial Intelligence in Continuum Mechanics," Journal of Engineering Mechanics Division, ASCE, Vol. VI, pp. 1239-65, Dec. 1970., 1970 December; 3189 (Box 28, Folder 65)
    - #91 - Bugliarello, G., A.K.C. Wong, T.K. Hung, M.H. Weissman, A.S. Ahuja and K.P. Stark, "Hydro-Bionics: A Perspective on Technological Implications of Biological Flows," Advances in Hydrobionics, Academic Press, Vol. 7, 1971, pp. 327-74., 3190 (Box 28, Folder 66)
    - #92 - Bugliarello, G., "Water Resources Planning: The Extension of the Systems Viewpoint," National Conference on Water, Rome, July, 1970., 1970 July; 3191 (Box 28, Folder 67)
    - #93 - Ahuja, A.S. and G. Bugliarello, "A Note on the Compressibility of Blood," Biorheology, Vol. 7, 1970, pp. 199-203., 3192 (Box 28, Folder 68)
    - #94 - Bugliarello, G., "Biomedical Engineering and the Changing Role of the University," Panel Discussion in "Engineering Medicine," NAE Symposium on Biomedical Engineering, Fourth Autumn Meeting, Washington, D.C. 1970., 3193 (Box 28, Folder 69)
    - #95 - Bugliarello, G., "Computer Languages and Design with Particular Reference to Hydraulic Design," Proceedings of the Symposium on the Water Environment and Human Needs, Published by Ralph M. Parson's Laboratory for Water Resources and Hydrodynamics, MIT, 1971, pp. 303-322., 1970; 3194 (Box 28, Folder 70)
    - #96 - Bugliarello, G.," Prospectives in Bioengineering for Civil Engineers," ASCE Journal of Professional Practice in Civil Engineering, October 1971, pp. 83-86., 1971 October; 3195 (Box 28, Folder 71)
    - #97 - Bugliarello, G., Closing Address, "State Science and Technology Interaction: A Cybernetic View," Proceedings, Midwestern Conference on Science, Technology and State Government, Nov. 1970, pp. 1-1--1-10., 1970 November; 3196 (Box 28, Folder 72)
    - #98 - Bugliarello, G., "Considerations for the Design of a Technological Forecasting Mechanism for Environmental Health," Environmental Letters, January 1971, pp. 141-50., 1971 January; 3197 (Box 28, Folder 73)
    - #99 - Hung, T.K., S. Kirch, L.J. Young and G. Bugliarello, "Model Studies of Hydrodynamic Characteristics of Erythrocyte-Shaped Bodies in a Tube," (Abstract) Proceedings of the 1971 Microcirculatory Society Meeting, Chicago, submitted December 1970., 1970 December; 3198 (Box 28, Folder 74)
    - #100 - Bugliarello, G., "Convective Diffusion in Cellular Laminar Flow in Tubes," Proceedings, XIV International IAHR Congress, Paris, France, Sept. 1971, Vol. 1, pp. 291-97., 1971 September; 3199 (Box 28, Folder 75)
    - #101 - Bugliarello, G., "Problem-Oriented Computer Languages in Hydraulic Engineering: A Brief Overview of Their Evolution, State of the Art and Future," Proceedings, XIV International IAHR Congress, Paris, France, Sept. 1971, Vol. 5, pp. 329-33., 1971 September; 3200 (Box 28, Folder 76)
    - #102 - Bugliarello, G., "A Covenant for the New Society," Proceedings of the 12th Annual Nuclear Engineering Education Conference, Argonne National Laboratory, Feb. 1971, pp. 3.2.1-3.2.8., 1971 February; 3201 (Box 28, Folder 77)
    - #103 - Bugliarello, G., T.K. Hung and C.E. Quevedo, "Fluid Flow," Chapter 3 in Biomedical Engineering, (Brown, Jacobs and Stark, Eds., F.A. Davis Co.) Pennsylvania, 1971, pp. 43-70., 3202 (Box 28, Folder 78)
    - #104 - Bugliarello, G., "Some Examples of Stochastic Modeling for Mass and Momentum Transfer," in Stochastic Hydraulics, C.L. Chiu, Ed., University of Pittsburgh Press, pp. 39-55. (Proceedings of the First International Symposium on Stochastics Hydraulics held at the University of Pittsburgh, May, 1971.), 1971 May; 3203 (Box 28, Folder 79)
    - #105 - Bugliarello, G., A. Cohen, W. Ham, Jr., J. Hardy, P. Hasterlik, E. Radford and D. Shimkin, "Man's Health and Physical Factors in the Environment: Some Research Needs," Ekistics 185, April, 1971, pp. 276-284., 1971 April; 3204 (Box 28, Folder 80)
    - #106 - Bugliarello, G., "Technological Innovation and Hydraulic Engineering," Journal of the Hydraulics Division, ASCE, Vol. 98, No. HY5, May 1972, pp. 751-64., 1972 May; 3205 (Box 28, Folder 81)
    - #107 - Bugliarello, G., "Biomechanics," Office of Naval Research International Symposium on Numerical and Computer Methods in Structural Mechanics, University of Illinois-Urbana, Sept. 1971, Academic Press, March, 1973., 1973 March; 3206 (Box 28, Folder 82)
    - #108 - Hung, T.C., T.K. Hung and G. Bugliarello, "The Flow of Blood in Small Curved Tubes," Proceedings, 24th Annual Conference on Engineering in Medicine and Biology, 1971, p. 169, 3207 (Box 28, Folder 83)
    - #109 - Bugliarello, G., "Rethinking Technology: Steady State Earth or Biosoma," World Development, World Development Press, August 1973, Vol. 1, #8., 1973 August; 3208 (Box 28, Folder 84)
    - #110 - Bugliarello, G., "Civil Engineering and National Goals in Bioengineering," Engineering Issues, Vol. 98, No. PP4, Oct. 1972, pp. 645-653., 1972 October; 3209 (Box 28, Folder 85)
    - #111 - Bugliarello, G., "Biorheology, Information Theory and Cybernetics," Biorheology, Sept. 1972, 1972 September; 3210 (Box 28, Folder 86)
    - #112 - Bugliarello, G., "The New Phase in Engineering Education: Engineering and the New Liberal Education," Engineering Education, Feb. 1973., 1973 February; 3211 (Box 28, Folder 87)
    - #113 - Simon, H. and G. Bugliarello, "Toward a Socio-Technology of High Rise Buildings," Proceedings, International Conference on Planning and Design of Tall Buildings, Lehigh University, Bethlehem, Pa., Sponsored by NSF in cooperation with ASCE-LABSE, Aug. 1972., 1972 August; 3212 (Box 28, Folder 88)
    - #114 - Gunther, F.J. and G. Bugliarello, "Computer-Instrument Packages and Data Banks in Environmental Data Collection: Some Central Issues and Trends," Proceedings, XVth International Congress of the International Association for Hydraulic Research, Istanbul, Sept. 1973., 1973 September; 3213 (Box 28, Folder 89)
    - #115 - Bugliarello, G., "Socio-Technology: The Emergence of a New Ideology and a New Methodology," Engineering Education, May 1973., 1973 May; 3214 (Box 28, Folder 90)